MacGYVER:
Now, this is what goin'
to the beach is all about.
( women shouting )
Boy, there's some
fine-lookin' women
out there, huh?
You got those binoculars?
Yeah, in the kitchen.
MacGYVER:
On the other hand,
rescuin' a lady general
has never been
my idea of beach fun.
( doorknob rattles )
All right, let's see
what we've got to work with.
Okay, this seems
to be a good start.
All I need is a few seconds
of distraction.
Oh, man,
look at that!
Oh, I gotta go outside
and check this out.
What the...?
Hey, let's go!
Come on!
Who's in there?
Hey!
( grunting )
I'll bet you didn't tell them
a thing, huh, General?
Let's get you outta here.
Handcuffs! Damn!
( men grunting and shouting )
( grunting )
She's gone!
( both yell )
( grunting and gasping )
Stay! Sit! Stay!
Good dogs.
Yeah, Packman? MacGyver.
You know that lady general
you lost?
Well, I found her.
MacGYVER:
I really have
to rethink my life.
I hardly get the lady general
back to the Pentagon
when I get a Code Red priority.
So, here I am on a moonlit
night starin' down the throat
of a brand-new Middle Eastern
nuclear refining plant
put on this good Earth
for no other reason
than to allow
some crazy strong man
to blow up his neighbors.
Guess what Washington
asked me to do.
All right, ready to blow it.
Be at the pickup zone at 0430.
All right.
Home-- enough is enough.
I will not,
under any circumstances
for any reason whatsoever
answer the phone...
probably... again.
Yes, I am definitely home.
Well?
I just dropped in
to congratulate you.
Thank you very much.
The Department
is grateful.
You're welcome.
And I'm very tired.
I'm not offering you
an assignment.
I'm giving you a warning.
You're a target.
Now, that I'd like
spelled out.
When you put away that
nuclear installation,
they ID'd you.
The contract went out
the next day.
They hired Axminster.
He took out Sheikh Hussein,
didn't he?
Right in the middle of prayers.
Blew him straight to Allah
and killed 37 others
along the way.
You oughta get out of town while
we, uh, stake this place out.
Barney, I like
to take care of my own messes.
MacGyver,
Axminster would torch
the whole block just to get you.
Now, I can set
up a safe house,
full security,
unless, uh,
you've got someplace
you'd like to settle in
for a couple of weeks.
You know, there
is a kind of a,
a trip I've been toying with.
Take it now.
As long as it spells one word:
"lost."
( sighs )
I guess I do owe a visit.
To who?
It's personal, Barney.
Okay, just tell me if and where.
I'll handle that, Colonel,
and you don't need
to know where.
You just take care of Axminster.
Take a look at this!
What?
It says this here lady
was attacked by aliens
and had an alien baby.
No kiddin'?
Yeah. In Alabama somewhere.
Big on aliens
in Alabama.
No lie.
Full of strange people.
That's why I'm goin' North,
back to see my family
for a while.
Makes sense.
MacGYVER:
I hadn't seen my grandfather
since I was ten.
He was all the family
I had left,
and we were strangers.
( phone ringing )
MacGYVER:
Hi. MacGyver here.
When you hear the beep,
let me know what's on your mind.
( beep )
JACKSON:
I'll let you know
what's on my mind, bud.
Pick up that phone
and talk to me.
I got no mind for machines.
Oh, damn,
I guess you aren't there!
This is your...
This is Harry Jackson.
The-the clerk
from the general store
brung me up a note
with this phone number.
He says you're comin'
to visit me.
Axminster!
JACKSON:
And I just want to say...
don't come.
I'm busy.
Ah, hell, you're probably
on the way here already.
You can phone the general store
again.
It's area code 303, triple-five,
double-seven-oh-two.
I'll try and run
that down right away.
MacGYVER:
What a beautiful part
of the world.
Has everything but people.
I got to wonder what happened
to my grandfather
that made him decide to live
in such isolation.
Actually, I wonder
if he'll even be here
to meet me.
WOMAN:
There he is...
Well, hop in.
Hi, Harry.
How'd you know?
I never forget
a grandfather.
You've grown.
Well, it's been, what, six,
17, 18 years, hasn't it?
I hadn't noticed.
Didn't get my message to you.
I tried to head you off.
You mind that I came?
( bird squawking )
Ah, what the hell.
You're here.
Well, come on.
I want to get home before dark.
Headlights don't work.
You haven't changed.
Haven't had to,
and I don't plan to.
All Right.
( seagull cawing )
All right.
Okay.
Thanks a lot.
The number's a general store
in a little town
in Colorado-- Ouray.
Harry Jackson
doesn't have a phone,
but they know him, Axminster.
They know where he lives.
( truck thudding )
You trying to throw me
or just scare me?
You always did
like to talk.
Still tough as a dirty boot,
aren't you?
You're damn right.
( door squeaking and closing )
Well?
Black, hot and strong, right?
Nothin' wrong
with your memory, bud.
Grandma used to say
you'd never drink a cup
of coffee
unless a spoon would stand up
in it.
Grandma never did
give up trying
to civilize me.
I guess maybe
that was the only
dumb mistake
she ever did make.
Except maybe dyin'.
Is that why you left us?
You always did get right
to the point.
Haven't changed.
Not much.
Want coffee?
Yeah.
You didn't answer me.
I left...
because it was time to leave.
No, when Dad died,
you were there.
I mean, you were...
I stayed around
for a while.
God, for the love of Mike, boy,
I still had the right
to my own life!
Doggone it, Harry,
I guess maybe it's...
how you did it.
I wake up one morning,
and you're gone.
I never liked good-byes.
I
took a job workin'
in construction up in Alaska.
Good job.
New country.
So I went.
I figured sending money regular
would be more use
to you and your mother
than I was.
You figured wrong.
That's your bunk.
Leave or stay, it's up to you.
We're ready
to roll, Axminster.
( engines starting )
How do you want
this guy MacGyver?
Dead or alive?
Dead.
( birds singing )
It's good.
Now, why are you here?
I guess I just got past
puttin' off this visit.
I haven't thought
about family in years.
Don't really want to now.
Harry, were you always
this hard-nosed?
Even when I was a kid?
( sighs )
I remember this.
JACKSON:
Uh...
Didn't I make this for you
when I was about ten?
For your birthday or something?
( quacking )
It works good, too.
Best I ever had.
CARSON:
Cabin's at the top
of the ridge, Axminster.
Then spread out.
We'll surround the
cabin and hit 'em.
So, you ready for some fishin'?
I already been.
What do you think
we're havin'
for breakfast?
Come on, Harry.
You're the one
that used to tell me
you don't fish for fish,
you fish for fishin'.
CARSON:
Cabin's empty,
Axminster!
( birds singing )
Nice.
Yeah, it's real nice.
Found this place
about eight years ago.
I'm stayin' right here
till I die.
Ah, you're too
mean to die.
What goes around comes around.
BLACK:
The truck's still
here, Axminster.
They got
to be close.
You know, I think Mom
and I missed you most
around Thanksgiving, Christmas.
I remember you used
to take me out
to cut a tree.
Stop riding it!
Is my being here
that hard on you?
Bud,
subject is closed.
( fishing line creaking )
I got one.
I got one!
JACKSON:
I said drag, bud. Watch it.
Ah, that's a beaut!
That's for dinner.
Don't let loose of him.
I'm not gonna let loose of him.
Get the net, Harry.
( gunshot )
Hey, what the...?
( gunshots )
Aah!
What the hell is goin' on?
I'll tell you
later. Come on.
Who are your friends?
Harry, I didn't think
they'd find me here.
They'll probably be
down here in a minute.
Let's go!
JACKSON:
Hollow reeds?
MacGYVER:
Yeah. We'll make 'em think
we're still out there
in the water.
They're too smart
for that one, boy.
Got to try something.
What if they do fall
for this stunt of yours, bud?
What do we get out of it?
Buy a little distance.
All depends on them
believin' that it's us
breathin'
under these reeds.
Have a little faith, Harry.
AXMINSTER:
Where the hell are they?
Down there,
those reeds!
Fire!
( rapid gunfire )
You, check it out.
They tricked us.
What are you
talking about?
MacGyver set us up.
Let's go tell Axminster.
Guess your friends
found those reeds
over on the other
side of the lake.
See, your grandson's got
something on the ball.
Hold it, Harry.
It's a plant from
the Urtica family.
Strong stuff.
One dab in the bloodstream
hits the neural system
and a guy's out for hours.
Blow gun?
I was thinking
along those lines.
Ah.
The only problem
we got, Harry,
in order for me
to knock them out,
I'm gonna have
to hit them just right.
Right in the neck.
What if you miss?
Okay, here we go.
HARRY:
Now we got a blow gun,
maybe help to make kind of
a trail for them to track us.
BLACK:
Hold it.
Their trail
leads down to the stream.
Hey, what's the matter?
Hey, hey, what's...?
( grunting )
( yells )
Nice.
Gotta hit them
just right.
Harry, can we get
out this way?
Don't seem to have
a lot of choice.
No.
Hold it!
Hold it
right there, bud.
Will you stop?
Now wait a minute!
I said hold it
right there!
Who are you, bud?
Now what the devil's
all this about?
I ain't moving
until I get an answer.
I'm sorry, Harry.
I shouldn't have come.
I underestimated
some things.
Just answer the question.
It has to do
with freedom
and peace, Harry.
And some people
who don't like either.
Well, I sure hope
it's worth losing
that damn trout.
They're still
alive, Axminster.
Shall we
pick them up?
AXMINSTER:
Forget them.
Move it.
We got a job to do.
Is there a ranger
station around?
How about
a fire lookout,
a ranch, anything?
Ah, let's see.
Evermore, uh,
it's a little,
old nothing town,
uh, half dead.
Well, now they got
a phone line.
How far is it?
Oh, it's ten to 12 miles.
It's up in
the high desert.
All right.
Let's move.
AXMINSTER:
Go that way.
We'll swing around
the hill and meet you.
CARSON:
Right.
HARRY:
Haven't done this much running
since two winters ago when
a grizzly was chasing me.
Did he
catch you?
HARRY:
Nah, got tired trying
to catch an old buzzard.
Hey, what are
you doing now?
Stop to collect
rocks?
CARSON:
Maybe up that way.
AXMINSTER:
Okay, we'll flush them out.
See anything?
MacGYVER:
Oh, I see a lot of things.
Anything I'd be
interested in?
Yeah.
Two jeeps splitting up.
Only one's
heading our way,
but he's gonna be
a while getting here, so I
figure we got a little time.
To do what?
Harry, don't you remember
teaching me all about decoys?
Why don't you fill
that up with branches?
Oh, yeah, and make it
look like a man.
Now let's see if I can get
this tree to do a few tricks.
AXMINSTER:
No sign of them coming this way.
CARSON:
Should I keep going?
AXMINSTER:
We should figure out MacGyver.
Then make a decision.
Alpha,
Colin, Baker,
do you read?
This is Axminster.
Are targets in sight?
No, sir.
No problem, it's just a little
cat and mouse. Keep moving.
You got your orders.
Over and out.
Okay?
Head up
to high ground.
AXMINSTER:
Yeah, it's a nice day
for hunting.
Hey, Harry?
Remember you used
to tell me about
how the Indians fought this way?
Bud...
a lot of
that stuff
I used to tell you
is, uh, is stories.
Yeah, well, a lot
of it works, Harry.
( Jeep approaching )
( yelling )
Damn.
Thought we'd at least get
a free ride out of this.
Guess we keep
on running.
MacGYVER:
That's Axminster.
Let's get going.
BLACK:
Axminster, the other jeep,
down in the gully.
AXMINSTER:
Two more down.
Let's finish this MacGyver now.
You getting lightheaded, bud?
Pinecones?
Sure, Harry.
Don't you remember ever
throwing one in a fire?
What happens?
It kind of explodes.
Yeah, that's right.
Add a little pine pitch and you
got the makings of a landmine.
Ain't Mother
Nature grand?
HARRY:
You just trying
to stay above them
or you got some
kind of an idea?
A little of both.
No, I can manage!
Hold it, Harry.
I figure the Jeep'll
come from there
right through here.
Well, what
in the...?
Time to bury the landmine.
HARRY:
See something?
MacGYVER:
Nope, but
I hear something.
HARRY:
Ought to get
a move on.
Ah, there's plenty of time.
You sure that'll work?
Nope.
Bud, you are a comfort.
HARRY:
Here they come.
Come on, let's go.
When I was a kid,
I used to chew
pine pitch like it was gum.
It tasted all right,
but it burned a lot better.
All right.
( rapid gunfire )
( grunting )
Harry?
I'm all right.
Get him!
( yelling )
Come on, Harry,
let's get moving.
AXMINSTER:
Can anybody still move?
CARSON:
Yeah, good enough
to find MacGyver.
BLACK:
Looks like we're
walking now, too.
AXMINSTER:
Not walk, run.
We'll run him right
into the ground.
Well, that's okay.
I'm just dinged.
Yeah,
so I noticed.
Just grazed
you, Harry.
Could've been
worse, you know.
Eh, hurts like worse.
Put that inside.
Put pressure on it.
You all right?
We made it.
Yeah.
HARRY:
Hey!
MacGYVER:
So... this
is Evermore.
( coughs )
Harry, when was the last
time you were here?
Too long ago.
It's dead.
I guess we are, too.
Harry? Harry! Harry!
Damn you, Axminster.
So, there we were
in a ghost town, Harry and me.
I tried to make him
as comfortable as possible.
What are you trying, bud?
That's fool's gold.
Which contains
pyrite-- iron sulfide.
Mixing it up
with a little clay here
kind of makes
a natural antibiotic.
Let's see
what you got here.
Just what is it
that you do, bud?
Well, a little of this,
a little of that.
( groans softly )
Well, that... that
sure explains it.
You're going
to be okay, Harry.
Ever think of
hanging out a shingle
as a medicine man?
I've got something
to say.
I've avoided you.
You know why?
Mom.
First your grandmother.
Then your mom.
When the good
Lord took them,
I hurt.
I didn't want to be reminded,
so I just, uh,
I just kept moving.
Seeing you...
I've missed you, bud.
Something terrible.
( softly ):
Harry...
( sighing )
Well, that... sure
was a sorry sight.
( sniffling )
Hey.
Don't you
ever badmouth my grandpa,
you hear?
( chuckling )
( groaning )
Look, I'm going
to try and find some things
for us to fight with.
What do you say?
You really think they're going
to find us here?
They're professionals, Harry.
They'll find us.
Harry had a good night's rest,
but I didn't sleep at all.
I knew that, with first light,
Axminster
would be tracking us again.
So, I had to build
the best defense I could
before they got to us.
Hey, bud!
Mind telling me
what you're doing?
Yeah, found some grain dust.
Treat it right,
we got the makings
of a pretty good bomb,
I'll betcha.
Might work good.
Got a little
parlor trick
to get them to come up close
to where the explosion happens.
Sometimes you hear
about floating grain dust
exploding inside a silo.
It's called
spontaneous combustion.
I'm going to do it on purpose.
And I found
a real handy partner in Harry.
He seemed to be talking
just the way I was.
Or maybe I'd been thinking
like him all along.
HARRY:
Only get one shot
with your exploding gadget,
bud.
MacCGYVER:
What you got in mind, Harry?
HARRY:
A little
remote control distraction.
Guaranteed to get them galoots
to come up real close
for the big surprise.
Hey, bud, I can play magician
from over here!
Now you see it, now you don't--
and boom!
All right, that's enough.
It's shaking,
and I don't want it
falling on my head.
Real trick's going
to be
getting those galoots
in position.
MacGYVER:
If they aren't
right underneath it,
it won't work.
Where are you going?
HARRY:
Come on.
I got a trick
of my own.
What do you got,
pine nuts?
HARRY:
Yeah, I used
to have fun with them
when I was a kid.
I'd, uh, drop them in the fire,
and watch everybody jump,
and they'd crack,
and they'd go off like gunshots.
Well, they've
been falling
for your foolishness.
I figured
I'd try some of my own.
I think Harry was beginning
to enjoy the game.
And that's all the time we had.
( clanking )
( men yelling )
( loud popping )
( man grunts )
Got him good.
Yeah.
We still have Axminster.
Only this time,
we got the odds.
Yeah.
Ow!
( grunting )
( gun cocking )
( gunshot )
Try, try to move him over, bud.
( grunting )
Now, bud!
( yelling )
You all right, bud?
I'm more than all right, Harry.
( groans )
Whew!
( both laugh )
You figuring
on coming back this way?
Count on it.
I'll look forward to it.
Me, too.
Hey, Harry...
catch that big old trout,
will you?
Count on it.
Take care
of yourself, bud.
( theme music playing )